Finding Aid for Division of Research Development and Administration (University of Michigan) Records, 1919-1996
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Directors’ Files
  - James Lesch (1969-1988)
    - Subject Files
      - Office of Vice President for Research
        - OVPR Correspondence File
          - Research "Incentive" Funds 1986 (Box 23)
      - Planning-OVPR/DRDA Retreat 1987 (Box 23)
      - Program for Executive Exchange and Research (PEER) 1984-1985 (Box 23)
      - Proprietary Information 1986-1987
        - Report sent to Regents 1986 (Box 23)
      - Reactor Laboratory-Operation of 1983 (Box 23)
      - Research Incentives 1983-1984
        - Task Force 1981, 1984-1985, 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Restrictions on Information-Federal 1984-1985 (Box 23)
      - Robotics Technology-Attracting Firms to the Ann Arbor Area 1981-1984 (Box 23)
      - Role of Research in the University-Report 1979 (Box 23)
      - Software Engineering Institute 1984-1985 (Box 23)
      - Spinoff Firms (from UM) 1984-1986 (Box 23)
      - Space Physics Research Laboratory 1977, 1983 (Box 23)
      - Technology Management 1981-1984 (Box 23)
      - Technology/Research Parks 1982-1986 (Box 23)
      - Technology Transfer 1982-1986, 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Tuition Grant/Remission 1985-1986 (Box 23)
      - U.S. Government-Office of Management and Budget-Circular A-21 1984-1987 (Box 23)
      - University/Industry Relationships 1979-1984, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - DRDA Correspondence Files 1983-1988 (Box 24)
    - Chronological Files
      - 1983-1987 (Box 24)
      - 1982-1991 (Box 25)
  - Allen Steiss 1988-1996
    - Chronological Files 1988-1996
      - May 1988-March 1989 (Box 31)
        [ER RESTRICTED until July 1, 2026 ]
      - April 1989-April 1990 (Box 32)
      - May 1990-February 1992 (Box 33)
      - March 1992-August 1993 (Box 34)
      - September 1993-October 1994 (Box 35)
      - November 1994-March 1996 (Box 36)
      - April 1996-November 1996 (Box 37)
    - Topical Files
      - Cold Fusion 1989 (Box 37)
      - Conflict of Interest 1988 (Box 37)
      - Costs of Research 1995 (Box 37)
      - Cost Accounting Standards 1995-1996, 3 folders (Box 37)
      - Faculty Fellows Research Program 1995 (Box 37)
      - Federal Demonstration Project
        - Evaluation of Federal Demo Project (Box 37)
        - Mid-Term Report (Box 37)
        - Organizational Structure (Box 37)
        - Summaries from Mac Cox (Box 37)
        - 1988-1989 (1 of 2 folders) (Box 37)
        - 1988-1989 (2 of 2 folders) (Box 38)
        - 1990-1995 (Box 38)
      - Federal Shutdown 1996 (Box 38)
      - Gifts, Grants and Contracts Guidelines 1985-1991 (Box 38)
      - Indirect Costs
        - A-21 Team circa 1994
          - General, 2 folders (Box 38)
          - At Risk -- In (Box 38)
          - At Risk -- Out (Box 38)
        - Indirect Cost Cap 1991 (Box 38)
        - Indirect Cost Rates 1989-1994 (Box 38)
        - Indirect Cost Rate Modification 1991 (Box 38)
        - Equipment Fabrication 1989-1995 (Box 38)
        - Equipment Thresholds 1995 (Box 38)
        - Gibbons / Rivlin Request for Feedback 1994 (Box 38)
        - Joint Administrative / Faculty Team on Indirect Costs 1991-1992 (Box 38)
        - Small Awards 1992 (Box 38)
      - Intellectual Property, Development of New Policy 1995-1996, 2 folders (Box 39)
      - M-Pathways
        - Administrative Information Technology Coordinating Committee (AITCC) Meetings 1993-1995, 3 folders (Box 39)
        - Class Codes 1995 (Box 39)
        - Cost Allocation Subcommittee 1993 (Box 39)
        - One Time Allocations 1993-1994 (Box 39)
        - Responsibility Center Management Implementation Team (RCMIT) 1994-1995, 4 folders (Box 39)
        - Strategic Data Planning -- Managing Financial Assets 1993-1994 (Box 40)
        - Value Centered Management (VCM)
          - General 1994-1996, 2 folders (Box 40)
          - Graduate Student Research Assistants (GSRAs) under VCM 1995 (Box 40)
      - Michigan Consortium for Enabling Technology (MCET)
        - General 1988-1992 (Box 40)
        - Planning and Policy Board 1990-1993 (Box 40)
      - Office of Vice President for Research
        - Communications 1988-1989 (Box 40)
        - Planning for Research, Research Portfolio, Recurring Research Issues 1989 (Box 40)
        - Report on Primary Research Scientists 1988-1995 (Box 40)
        - Staff Meetings and Agendas 1988-1989, 2 folders (Box 40)
        - Unit Directors' Meetings 1989-1993 (Box 40)
        - Miscellaneous 1987-1989 (Box 40)
      - Overruns and Disallowances 1989-1996 (Box 41)
      - Overrun, Department of Energy 1993-1994 (Box 41)
      - Performance Evaluation 1991-1993 (Box 41)
      - President's Annual Report 1987-1988 (Box 41)
      - Regents' Communication 1988-1989 (Box 41)
      - Research Associate Deans 1988-1997, 7 folders (Box 41)
      - Research Expenditures 1994-1995 (Box 41)
      - Research Policies Committee 1989-1990, 1993-1995, 2 folders (Box 41)
      - Review Committee 1993-1994 (Box 42)
      - Routine Commercial Testing 1988-1992 (Box 42)
      - Sales of Goods and Services Policy 1990 (Box 42)
      - Staff Meeting Minutes 1988-1990, 3 folders (Box 42)
- Research Grant Files 1926-1969
  The Research Grant Files comprise 326 rolls of microfilm housed in five boxes, on which are stored copies of grant files that were destroyed after microfilming. The files date from 1926 to 1969, and are arranged according to date and project number. An index identifying which project number appears on which reel is contained in box 26. A partial file of project numbers and dates is also contained in box 26. A card catalog of projects was maintained by DRDA and has not been transferred to the archives.
  - Microfilm of grant files
    (326 reels of 16mm microfilm with index in Box 26)
    - Microfilm of grant files (Box 26)
    - Microfilm of grant files (Box 27)
      (continued)
    - Microfilm of grant files (Box 28)
    - Microfilm of grant files (Box 29)
    - Microfilm of grant files (Box 30)
- Programmed Research Information System at Michigan (PRISM) Reports
  Programmed Research Information System at Michigan (PRISM) Reports contains the Weekly Report of Research Activities from January 4, 1985 through March 18, 1988. Information contained in the reports includes Proposal Number, Title, Project Director, Submitted to and date, Time in months, and Proposed Amount ($).
  - January 4, 1985-March 18, 1988 (Box 43)
Related Material
For related materials, the researcher should also consult the papers of Robert E. Burroughs, Albert E. White, and the records of the Office of the Vice-President for Research and its related collections.